Anyone can visit. You
can swim where Grant
walked and surf where
Garfield was carried to
die. On the grounds
of the Church of
the Pres idents there
is a small tea
house. It was built
from the actual railroad
ties that volunteers laid
through the night to
bring a dying president
to the sea. One
of the original iron
rails serves as its
ridge pole, seven presidents,
four undeniable, three debatable.
But the stories they
left behind of power,
of tragedy, of a
community pushing a train
car by hand, those
are real. This is
the first of five
videos. Next, Grant's poker
games and financial ruin.
Then the full Garfield
story, 79 days, then
Wilson's broken promise and
the resort itself ,
the hotels, the gamblers,
and the fire. Subscribe
so you do not
miss them.