But the other Presidents,
Hayes spent his summers
in Washington. Researchers have
found no evidence placing
him near Long Branch.
Harrison is a Cape
May man. His summer
White House was over
a hundred miles to
the South. Arthur, his
most documented visit was
the night he came
to comfort the widow
of the man whose
murder made him President.
Three of the seven
are at best on
thin ice. But try
renaming it for Presidents
Park. Two more Presidents
have strong connections to
Long Branch. In 1899,
William McKinley came to
deliver a defense of
the American flag at
Ocean Grove's great auditorium
and to visit his
ailing Vice President Garrett
Hobart in West Long
Branch. Two years later,
McKinley was assassinated. The
second President in the
seven President's story killed
in office. And then
Woodrow Wilson. In 1916,
Wilson moved into Shadow
Lawn,