Seven Presidents Ocean Front
Park. 38 acres of
public beach on the
Jersey Shore. The name
promises that seven American
Presidents once called this
stretch of Shoreline home.
The truth, the real
number might be four,
maybe five. But the
stories behind these men,
of ambition, of tragedy,
of a community building
a railroad overnight to
save a dying President,
are far more extraordinary
than any myth. The
story begins with a
chapel. In 1925, St.
James Chapel on Ocean
Avenue was on the
verge of closing. A
local benefactor saved it,
and his attorney declared
the chapel had been
attended by six American
Presidents. He called it
the Westminster Abbey of
America. By 1930, a
seventh name was added.
The park that opened
nearby was Chrison's seven
Presidents Ocean Front Park.