This beach is named
after seven presidents. The
real number may be
four. Ulysses Grant came
first. He held cabinet
meetings on the porch
and played poker with
America's wealthiest men every
Friday night. Then Garfield
was shot. The bullet
missed every vital organ
. It was the
infections that killed him.
Volunteers laid 3,200 feet
of track overnight by
torchlight to bring a
dying president to the
sea. The Elbrin hotel
sent sandwiches. Today, a
small tea house still
stands on the church
grounds, built from those
very railroad ties. The
original red paint has
faded to pink after
140 years of shore
weather. Woodrow Wilson ran
his entire campaign from
a 52 room beach
house. His slogan, he
kept us out of
war. Five months later,
he asked Congress to
declare war.