Then came prohibition, and the same skills that made the men of Monmouth County legendary fishermen made them exceptional criminals.
Monmouth County was perfectly suited for smuggling, riddled with small inlets and streams, home to experienced seamen and boat builders.
The fisherman's traditional sea-bright skiff was modified into something new, souped up speedboats that could outrun Coast Guard cutters.
On the darkest nights, the rum runners would race into the shallows of Raritan Bay, run their flat bottom skiffs up onto the beach, hand off crates of whiskey to a waiting truck, and vanish before the law arrived.