4 pounds. Paid in blankets, clothing and hardware, roughly 11 cents an acre.
As settlements grew along the shore, so did the shipwrecks.
Between 1846 and 1848 alone, more than 120 vessels wrecked along the New Jersey coast.
And with each disaster came a damning rumor that the locals were not just salvaging the wreckage.
They were causing it.
The people of Monmouth County were branded bandits and land pirates.
Newspapers accused them of hanging false lights to confuse ships captains,
driving vessels onto sand bars so they could plunder the cargo.
In 1799, the New Jersey legislature made it a crime to display false lights to induce a shipwreck.