IN DECEMBER 2025, A
STARTUP CALLED STARCLOUD PUT
A SINGLE NVIDIA H100
GPU INTO ORBIT. 60
KILOGRAMS, ONE CHIP. THEY
TRAINED A SMALL LANGUAGE
MODEL ON IT, AND
INVESTORS RESPONDED WITH $170
MILLION AND A BILLION
-DOLLAR VALUATION. TWO MONTHS
LATER, THEY FILED WITH
THE FCC TO BUILD
A CONSTELLATION OF 88
,000 SATELLITES. THAT WOULD
BE NEARLY NINE TIMES
THE SIZE OF STARLINK.
NOT FOR INTERNET. FOR
COMPUTING. MEANWHILE, ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF THIS
STORY, 70 ,000 OFFSHORE
OIL WORKERS IN THE
UK HAVE LOST THEIR
JOBS IN THE LAST
DECADE. IN THE GULF
OF MEXICO, NEARLY 100
,000 MORE. ENTIRE COMMUNITIES
BUILT AROUND THE OCEAN,
THE RIGS, THE SUPPLY
BOATS, THE WELDING SHOPS,
ARE WATCHING THEIR INDUSTRY
DIE, AND ALMOST NOBODY
IS CONNECTING THESE TWO
FACTS. THIS IS THAT
STORY. TO BE FAIR,
THE OUTER SPACE PITCH
IS COMPELLING. IN ORBIT,
SOLAR PANELS GENERATE ROUGHLY
FIVE TIMES MORE ENERGY
THAN ON THE GROUND.
NO CLOUDS, NO NIGHT
CYCLE IN A SUN'S
SYNCHRONOUS ORBIT, NO ATMOSPHERE
TO FILTER THE LIGHT.
RADIATIVE COOLING TO THE
VACUUM OF SPACE MEANS
YOU NEVER NEED WATER
FOR COOLING, AND YOU
NEVER HAVE TO NEGOTIATE
WITH A COUNTY PLANNING
BOARD FOR A BUILDING
PERMIT. THE MONEY IS
REAL. STARCLOUD, BACKED BY
BENCHMARK AND EQT, HAS
RAISED $200 MILLION AND
IS BUILDING ITS SECOND
SATELLITE FOR OCTOBER LAUNCH.
ORBITAL, FUNDED BY ANDRESEN
HOROWITZ JUST THIS MONTH,
IS TARGETING AN APRIL
2027 TEST FLIGHT WITH
NVIDIA GPUS. THALES, THE
EUROPEAN DEFENSE GIANT, HAS
A CONCEPT DESIGNED FOR
A 10 -MEGAWATT ORBITAL
DATA CENTER, BUT THEIR
TARGET DATE IS 2036,
AND GOOGLE AND NVIDIA
HAVE RUN EXPLORATORY JOINT
TESTS. THE LONG -TERM
VISION GOES EVEN FURTHER.
SOME PROPONENTS INVOKE THE
DYSON SPHERE, THE THEORETICAL
STRUCTURE THAT CAPTURES ALL
ENERGY FROM A STAR.
SPACE DATA CENTERS, THEY
ARGUE, ARE THE FIRST
STEP TOWARD THAT FUTURE.
IT IS A BEAUTIFUL
IDEA, BUT THERE IS
A PROBLEM. A 10
-MEGAWATT DATA CENTER IN
OUTER SPACE, ROUGHLY ENOUGH
TO RUN A MID
-SIZE AI TRAINING CLUSTER,
WOULD COST BETWEEN $1
.6 AND $11 BILLION
IN CAPITAL ALONE. ITS
OPERATIONAL LIFESPAN? TWO TO
FIVE YEARS. THERE IS
NO MAINTENANCE. WHEN A
COMPONENT FAILS, THE ENTIRE
SATELLITE IS A WRITE
-OFF. YOU CANNOT SEND
A TECHNICIAN TO LOW
EARTH ORBIT. A 10
-MEGAWATT DATA CENTER IN
INNER SPACE, FLOATING ON
AN OFFSHORE WIND PLATFORM
OR HOUSED INSIDE A
REPURPOSED OIL RIG, COSTS
BETWEEN $160 AND $530
MILLION. IT LASTS 25
TO 30 YEARS, AND
WHEN SOMETHING BREAKS, YOU
DISPATCH A REMOTELY OPERATED
VEHICLE, AN ROV, $30
,000 A DAY TO
RENT. THEY ALREADY EXIST
BY THE THOUSANDS. OVER
25 YEARS, THE TOTAL
COST OF OWNERSHIP FOR
A 10 -MEGAWATT OUTER
SPACE DATA CENTER EXCEEDS
$25 BILLION. REPLACEMENTS, LAUNCHES,
ORBITAL DECAY, INSURANCE, IF
YOU CAN EVEN GET
IT. THE SAME CAPACITY
IN THE OCEAN? THREE
TO FOUR BILLION TOTAL.
PLATFORM, POWER, COOLING, MAINTENANCE,
EVERYTHING. AND THEN THERE
IS LATENCY. A DATA
CENTER IN LOW EARTH
ORBIT ADDS 20 TO
50 MILLISECONDS OF ROUND
-TRIP DELAY. FOR AI
INFERENCE, THE WORKLOAD THAT
ACTUALLY MAKES MONEY, THE
ONE THAT ANSWERS YOUR
QUESTIONS AND GENERATES YOUR
IMAGES IN REAL TIME,
THAT DELAY IS A
DEAL BREAKER. AN OCEAN
DATA CENTER 130 KILOMETERS
OFFSHORE, 0 .65 MILLISECONDS,
EFFECTIVELY INVISIBLE. IN 2018,
MICROSOFT SANK 864 SERVERS
TO THE BOTTOM OF
THE OCEAN OFF SCOTLAND,
PROJECT NATICK. THEY SEALED
THEM IN A NITROGEN
-FILLED CAPSULE, DROPPED IT
35 METERS DOWN, AND
LEFT IT THERE FOR
TWO YEARS. THE RESULTS
WERE REMARKABLE. THE FAILURE
RATE WAS EIGHT TIMES
LOWER THAN AN EQUIVALENT
LAND -BASED DATA CENTER.
EIGHT TIMES. THE COLD,
STABLE TEMPERATURE OF THE
DEEP OCEAN AND THE
ABSENCE OF HUMAN INTERVENTION.
NO ONE OPENING DOORS,
NO DUST, NO HUMIDITY
FLUCTUATIONS MADE THE SERVERS
DRAMATICALLY MORE RELIABLE. MICROSOFT
CANCELED NATICK IN 2024,
NOT BECAUSE IT FAILED.
IT WAS ONE OF
THE MOST SUCCESSFUL INFRASTRUCTURE
EXPERIMENTS OF THE DECADE.
THEY CANCELED IT BECAUSE
THEY NEEDED HYPERSCALE CAMPUS
CAPACITY FOR AI, AND
THE POD MODEL DID
NOT FIT THAT STRATEGY.
THE TECHNOLOGY WAS PROVEN.
THE BUSINESS CASE JUST
POINTED SOMEWHERE ELSE, BUT
OTHER COMPANIES WERE PAYING
ATTENTION. IN HAINAN, CHINA,
HIGHLANDER HAS DEPLOYED THE
WORLD'S FIRST COMMERCIAL UNDERWATER
DATA CENTER. OPERATIONAL RIGHT
NOW, 1 ,200 SERVERS
IN SEALED CAPSULES ON
THE SEAFLOOR WITH PLANS
FOR 100 CAPSULES. THEY
HAVE CONNECTED A SEPARATE
FACILITY NEAR SHANGHAI DIRECTLY
TO AN OFFSHORE WIND
FARM, THE FIRST WIND
-POWERED UNDERWATER DATA CENTER
ON EARTH. IN THE
NORTH SEA, AIKIDO TECHNOLOGIES
IS DEPLOYING A PROTOTYPE
THIS YEAR, A FLOATING
WIND PLATFORM WITH A
DATA CENTER BUILT INTO
THE BALLAST TANKS UNDERNEATH.
NVIDIA IS A PARTNER.
THEIR COMMERCIAL LAUNCH TARGETS
THE UK IN 2028.
PROJECTED PUE? 1 .08.
IN CALIFORNIA, NAUTILUS DATA
TECHNOLOGIES BUILT A 7
-MEGAWATT FLOATING DATA CENTER
IN STOCKTON, A BARGE
THAT USES RIVER WATER
FOR COOLING. 86 %
OCCUPIED. IN THE GULF
OF MEXICO, HYPERSCALE DATA
RAN A DATA CENTER
ON A REPURPOSED OIL
PLATFORM FROM NOVEMBER 2024
THROUGH FEBRUARY 2025, PROVING
THE CONCEPT WITH EXISTING
INFRASTRUCTURE. BELOW THE SURFACE,
NETWORK OCEAN, A Y
-COMBINATOR STARTUP, IS TESTING
A 1 -MEGAWATT UNDERWATER
CAPSULE IN SAN FRANCISCO
BAY. SUBSEA CLOUD HAS
PROJECTS IN WASHINGTON STATE,
THE GULF OF MEXICO,
AND THE NORTH SEA.
THESE ARE NOT CONCEPTS.
THEY ARE IN THE
WATER. HERE IS SOMETHING
MOST PEOPLE DO NOT
REALIZE. 99 % OF
ALL INTERNATIONAL INTERNET TRAFFIC
ALREADY TRAVELS THROUGH THE
OCEAN. 1 .5 MILLION
KILOMETERS OF SUBMARINE FIBER
OPTIC CABLE SIT ON
THE SEAFLOOR RIGHT NOW.
THE BACKBONE OF THE
INTERNET IS NOT IN
THE CLOUD. IT IS
IN INNER SPACE. AN
OCEAN DATA CENTER DOES
NOT NEED A NEW
NETWORK. IT PLUGS INTO
THE ONE THAT ALREADY
EXISTS. THERE ARE 12
,000 OFFSHORE OIL AND
GAS PLATFORMS IN THE
WORLD. MANY ARE APPROACHING
END OF LIFE. AND
HERE IS THE ABSURDITY.
GOVERNMENTS ARE ABOUT TO
SPEND STAGGERING AMOUNTS OF
MONEY TO DESTROY THEM.
THE UK ALONE HAS
BUDGETED 44 BILLION POUNDS,
56 BILLION DOLLARS, TO
DECOMMISSION ITS NORTH SEA
PLATFORMS. THE GULF OF
MEXICO FACES 40 TO
70 BILLION IN DEMOLITION
COSTS. EVERY ONE OF
THOSE PLATFORMS ALREADY HAS
GAS TURBINES FOR POWER,
CRANES FOR LIFTING EQUIPMENT,
HELIPADS FOR ACCESS, AND
SEAWATER INTAKES FOR COOLING.
EVERYTHING A DATA CENTER
NEEDS, WE ARE PAYING
TO DEMOLISH READY -MADE
INNER SPACE DATA CENTER
SITES WHILE POURING VENTURE
CAPITAL INTO OUTER SPACE
ONES. AND THOSE PLATFORMS
WERE NOT BUILT BY
SOFTWARE ENGINEERS. THEY WERE
BUILT BY MARINE ELECTRICIANS,
ROV OPERATORS, SUBSEA CABLE
CREWS, CRANE OPERATORS, AND
PLATFORM MANAGERS. THE SAME
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOW
BEING LAID OFF AT
A RATE OF 400
EVERY TWO WEEKS IN
THE UK ALONE. ABERDEEN,
THE OIL CAPITAL OF
EUROPE, HAS LOST 18
,000 JOBS SINCE 2014.
IT IS ONE OF
ONLY TWO CITIES IN
THE ENTIRE UK WITH
FEWER JOBS THAN IT
HAD IN 2010. IN
LOUISIANA, 25 ,000 OFFSHORE
WORKERS HAVE LOST THEIR
JOBS SINCE 2014. OIL
WENT FROM A THIRD
OF THE STATE ECONOMY
TO 14 PERCENT. IN
NORWAY, EQUINOR EXPECTS 10
,000 EMPLOYEES TO RETIRE
BY 2030, THE LARGEST
RESTRUCTURING IN THE COMPANY'S
20 -YEAR HISTORY. 48
PERCENT OF US ENERGY
WORKERS ARE 45 OR
OLDER, AGING OUT OF
AN INDUSTRY WITH NO
REPLACEMENT PIPELINE. BUT HERE
IS WHAT MAKES THIS
STORY SO FRUSTRATING. THESE
WORKERS ALREADY HAVE THE
SKILLS. AN ROV OPERATOR
WHO INSPECTED SUBSEA PIPELINES
FOR 30 YEARS CAN
INSPECT SUBSEA DATA CENTER
PODS WITH EXACT SAME
EQUIPMENT. A SUBSEA ENGINEER
WHO DESIGNED PRESSURE VESSELS
FOR OIL? THE SAME
PRESSURE VESSELS HOUSE UNDERWATER
SERVERS, MARINE ELECTRICIANS, SUBSEA
CABLE CREWS, CRANE OPERATORS.
THESE ARE NOT ADJACENT
SKILLS. THEY ARE IDENTICAL
JOBS WITH A DIFFERENT
MISSION. OEUK, THE UK'S
OFFSHORE ENERGY TRADE BODY,
FOUND THAT 90 PERCENT
OF OIL AND GAS
SKILLS ARE DIRECTLY TRANSFERABLE,
NOT 50, NOT 70,
90. ONE OFFSHORE WORKER
PUT IT SIMPLY, AS
LONG AS IT PAID
THE BILLS, IT WOULDN'T
MATTER TO ME. IF
I CAN COME HOME
TO MY FAMILY, THAT'S
WHAT MATTERS. A UNION
ENGINEER SAID, RIGGING IS
RIGGING. IT DOESN'T MATTER
IF YOU'RE ON AN
OIL RIG IN A
FABRICATION YARD OR ON
A ONE TURBINE. RIGHT
NOW, THE GLOBAL OIL
INDUSTRY FLARES 151 BILLION
CUBIC METERS OF NATURAL
GAS EVERY YEAR. JUST
BURNS IT. WASTED. THAT
IS ENOUGH ENERGY TO
POWER EVERY DATA CENTER
IN THE UNITED STATES.
CRUSOE ENERGY PROVED THE
MODEL ON LAND. DATA
CENTERS NEXT TO WELLHEADS.
CAPTURING FLARED GAS FOR
ELECTRICITY. 63 PERCENT CO2
REDUCTION VERSUS JUST LETTING
IT BURN. 250 MEGAWATTS
DEPLOYED. NOW WORTH BILLIONS.
AND OFFSHORE WIND IS
NO LONGER EXPERIMENTAL. 84
.5 GIGAWATTS OF CAPACITY
IS INSTALLED WORLDWIDE TODAY.
THAT IS NEARLY ENOUGH
TO POWER EVERY DATA
CENTER ON EARTH. THE
ENERGY IS ALREADY BEING
GENERATED. IT JUST NEEDS
SOMEWHERE TO GO. LAND
-BASED DATA CENTERS HAVE
A WATER PROBLEM THAT
IS GETTING WORSE EVERY
YEAR. IN 2020, THREE
U .S. DATA CENTERS
CONSUMED AN ESTIMATED 66
BILLION LITERS OF WATER
DIRECTLY AND 800 BILLION
LITERS INDIRECTLY THROUGH ELECTRICITY
GENERATION. GOOGLE ALONE USED
8 .1 BILLION GALLONS.
TWO -THIRDS OF NEW
DATA CENTER CONSTRUCTION IS
HAPPENING IN WATER -STRESSED
REGIONS AND OCEAN DATA
CENTERS USES ZERO FRESH
WATER. THE OCEAN IS
THE HEAT SINK. COLD
SEA WATER FLOWS THROUGH
HEAT EXCHANGERS AND RETURNS
A FEW DEGREES WARMER.
NO EVAPORATIVE COOLING TOWERS.
NO MUNICIPAL WATER DRAW.
NO COMPETING WITH FARMS
AND FAMILIES FOR A
RESOURCE THAT IS RUNNING
OUT. NOW CONSIDER WHAT
88 ,000 SATELLITES WOULD
DO TO THE SKY.
EACH FALCON 9 LAUNCH
DEPOSITS ROUGHLY 425 TONS
OF CO2 INTO THE
ATMOSPHERE. BUT THE REAL
DAMAGE IS THE BLACK
CARBON. SOOT PARTICLES INJECTED
DIRECTLY INTO THE STRATOSPHERE
WHERE THEY ARE 500
TIMES MORE EFFECTIVE AT
TRAPPING HEAT THAN THE
SAME PARTICLES AT GROUND
LEVEL. A 2025 STUDY
FROM ETH ZURICH FOUND
THAT PROJECTED LAUNCH RATES
WILL MEASURABLY SLOW THE
RECOVERY OF THE OZONE
LAYER. EVERY SATELLITE THAT
REACHES END OF LIFE
BURNS UP ON RE
-ENTRY SCATTERING RARE EARTH
METALS AND ALUMINUM OXIDE
AS AEROSOLS INTO THE
UPPER ATMOSPHERE. NO RECYCLING.
NO RECOVERY. 100 %
E -WASTE VAPORIZED INTO
THE AIR WE BREATHE.
THERE ARE ALREADY 54
,000 TRACKED OBJECTS IN
ORBIT. THE PREDICTED INTERVAL
BETWEEN SIGNIFICANT COLLISION EVENTS,
THE CRASH CLOCK, SITS
AT 2 .8 DAYS.
ADDING 88 ,000 MORE
OBJECTS TO THAT ENVIRONMENT
IS NOT A CALCULATED
RISK. IT IS A
BET AGAINST PHYSICS. MEANWHILE,
IN INNER SPACE, SOMETHING
UNEXPECTED HAPPENS WHEN YOU
PUT STRUCTURES IN THE
WATER. OIL PLATFORM BASES
IN THE GULF OF
MEXICO HAVE BECOME SOME
OF THE MOST PRODUCTIVE
ARTIFICIAL REEFS ON THE
PLANET. 12 TO 14
,000 FISH PER STRUCTURE.
THE RIGS TO REEFS
PROGRAM HAS BEEN CONVERTING
DECOMMISSIONED PLATFORMS INTO PERMANENT
MARINE HABITATS FOR DECADES.
A DATA CENTER ON
A PLATFORM DOES NOT
JUST PRESERVE THE REEF.
IT FUNDS ITS PROTECTION.
LOOK, I RESPECT THE
AMBITION. THE DREAM OF
COMPUTING IN OUTER SPACE
IS GENUINELY INSPIRING. SOMEDAY
MAYBE. BUT A DYSON
SPHERE IS NOT A
ROADMAP. IT IS A
THOUGHT EXPERIMENT. MEANWHILE, OFFSHORE
WIND IS ALREADY SPINNING.
SUBMARINE CABLES ARE ALREADY
CARRYING YOUR DATA. OIL
PLATFORMS ARE ALREADY STANDING
IN THE WATER, WAITING
FOR THEIR NEXT JOB.
$200 MILLION BOUGHT ONE
GPU IN ORBIT. THAT
SAME CAPITAL COULD FUND
MULTIPLE MEGAWATT SCALE OCEAN
DATA CENTERS THAT ARE
OPERATIONAL TODAY. STARCLOUD HAS
RAISED MONEY TO BUILD
A SECOND SATELLITE. AIKIDO
HAS AN NVIDIA PARTNERSHIP
AND A PROTOTYPE GOING
INTO THE WATER THIS
YEAR. HIGHLANDER IS ALREADY
RUNNING COMMERCIAL OPERATIONS. INNER
SPACE IS NOT A
CONCEPT. IT IS A
BUSINESS. OUTER SPACE DATA
CENTERS ARE BUILT IN
LOS ANGELES, REDMOND, CAPE
CANAVERAL, SILICON VALLEY. THEY
NEED AEROSPACE ENGINEERS, ORBITAL
MECHANIC SPECIALISTS, SATELLITE SYSTEMS
DESIGNERS, SKILLS THAT DO
NOT EXIST IN OIL
COMMUNITIES. THEY EMPLOY HUNDREDS
OF HIGHLY SPECIALIZED ENGINEERS
IN CITIES THAT ALREADY
HAVE PLENTY OF JOBS.
INNER SPACE DATA CENTERS
ARE BUILT BY MARINE
TECHNICIANS, ROV OPERATORS, SUBSEA
ENGINEERS, PEOPLE WHO ALREADY
LIVE IN ABERDEEN, HUMA,
STAVANGER, AND A HUNDRED
OTHER COASTAL TOWNS. THEY
DO NOT NEED TO
MOVE TO CALIFORNIA. THEY
RETRAIN FOR A CAREER
THEY HAVE NEVER HEARD
OF. THEY STAY WHERE
THEY ARE AND KEEP
DOING WHAT THEY KNOW
WITH A NEW MISSION.
AND THIS IS NOT
JUST ABOUT THE WORKERS
ON THE PLATFORM. EACH
OFFSHORE ENERGY JOB SUPPORTS
ROUGHLY 1 .8 ADDITIONAL
ONSHORE JOBS. THE SUPPLY
BOAT CREWS, THE PORT
WORKERS, THE WELDING SHOPS,
THE DINERS. IN DEEP
WATER, THAT MULTIPLIER RISES
TO FOUR. ABERDEEN, THE
OIL CAPITAL OF EUROPE,
IS SEARCHING FOR A
NEW IDENTITY. HUMA, LOUISIANA,
THE OFFSHORE CAPITAL OF
THE U .S. GULF,
HAS THE SAME SUPPLY
BOATS THAT COULD SERVICE
DATA CENTER PODS TOMORROW.
THERE IS A PAY
GAP. EXPERIENCED OIL WORKERS
EARN $100 ,000 TO
$200 ,000. OFFSHORE WIND
PAYS AROUND $72 ,000
AT THE 90TH PERCENTILE.
BUT OCEAN DATA CENTERS
ARE HIGHER MARGIN OPERATIONS
THAN WIND FARMS. THEY
COULD PLAUSIBLY CLOSE THAT
GAP. AND A JOB
THAT EXISTS BEATS A
PERFECT JOB THAT DOES
NOT. BUT HERE IS
THE PART OF THE
STORY NOBODY SAW COMING.
IN 2005, ACCORDING TO
REISTAT ENERGY, GLOBAL CAPITAL
EXPENDITURE ON DATA CENTERS
REACHED $770 BILLION. THAT
SURPASSED UPSTREAM OIL AND
GAS INVESTMENT FOR THE
FIRST TIME IN HISTORY.
GOLDMAN SACHS PROJECTS. DATA
CENTER POWER DEMAND WILL
GROW 165 % BY
2030. THE IEA FORECASTS
945 TERAWATT HOURS. GROWING
FOUR TIMES FASTER THAN
EVERY OTHER SECTOR COMBINED,
THE OIL COMPANIES READ
THESE NUMBERS TOO, AND
THEY ARE NOT SITTING
STILL. CHEVRON IS BUILDING
4 GIGAWATTS OF GAS
-FIRED POWER FOUNDRIES, THEIR
WORD, CO -LOCATED DIRECTLY
WITH DATA CENTERS. BEHIND
THE METER, NO GRID
REQUIRED. THEIR CEO CALLED
IT A CORRAL NET.
IT REALLY DOES MAKE
GOOD SENSE. EXXONMOBIL IS
CONSTRUCTING A 1 .2
GIGAWATT GAS PLANT WITH
90 % CARBON CAPTURE,
PURPOSE BUILT FOR A
HYPERSCALER DATA CENTER. THEIR
CEO'S PITCH TO INVESTORS,
WE WILL BRING THIS
ON FASTER THAN ANYBODY
ELSE. TOTAL ENERGIES HAS
SIGNED CONTRACTS WITH GOOGLE
TO POWER DUTCH DATA
CENTERS AND A 610
GIGAWATT HOUR DEAL WITH
DATA 4 IN SPAIN.
EQUINOR CREATED AN ENTIRELY
NEW BUSINESS UNIT IN
APRIL 2025, JUST CALLED
IT POWER, CITING GROWING
DEMAND FROM AI AND
DATA CENTERS. AND IN
MARCH OF THIS YEAR,
ACREBP AND ARMADA PUT
THE FIRST AI DATA
CENTER ON A LIVE
OFFSHORE OIL PLATFORM ON
THE NORWEGIAN CONTINENTAL SHELF.
THEY CALLED IT A
REFERENCE SYSTEM. THAT IS
AN OIL INDUSTRY TERM.
IT MEANS A TEMPLATE
TO COPY EVERYWHERE. THE
OIL FIELD SERVICES COMPANIES
ARE MOVING EVEN FASTER.
BAKER HUGHES HAS BOOKED
1 .2 GIGAWATTS OF
DATA CENTER WORK. HALLIBURTON'S
VOLTAGRID SUBSIDIARY SIGNED A
2 .3 GIGAWATT DEAL
WITH ORACLE. SLB'S DIGITAL
DIVISION HIT $1 BILLION
IN ANNUAL RECURRING REVENUE,
UP 121 % YEAR
OVER YEAR. HALLIBURTON'S CEO
PUT IT BLUNTLY, THE
DEMAND FOR POWER AND
AI IS LIKE NOTHING
I HAVE EVER SEEN.
AND THE ENERGY IS
ALREADY THERE. ARMADA ESTIMATES
SIX GIGAWATTS OF STRANDED
ENERGY EXISTS IN THE
UNITED STATES ALONE. GAS
THAT IS BEING FLARED
OR SHUT IN, BECAUSE
THERE IS NO PIPELINE
TO TAKE IT ANYWHERE.
THAT IS ENOUGH TO
POWER HUNDREDS OF DATA
CENTERS. SHELL'S LATEST SCENARIOS
PREDICT DATA CENTERS WILL
CONSUME 5 ,000 TERAWATT
HOURS BY 2050, ROUGHLY
8 % OF ALL
GLOBAL ELECTRICITY. THESE COMPANIES
BUILT THE MODERN WORLD,
THE ENERGY THAT POWERED
THE INTERNET, THE CITIES,
THE HOSPITALS. IT CAME
FROM THEM. THEY ARE
NOT THE ENEMY OF
WHAT COMES NEXT. THEY
ARE THE BRIDGE TO
IT. THE PLATFORMS EXIST.
THE WORKFORCE EXISTS. THE
LOGISTICS EXIST. THE ONLY
THING LEFT IS TO
POINT IT ALL IN
THE RIGHT DIRECTION. AND
THEY ALREADY ARE. THE
INFRASTRUCTURE IS THERE. THE
POWER IS THERE. THE
COOLING IS LITERALLY INFINITE.
THE WORKFORCE ALREADY EXISTS.
THE OIL COMPANIES ARE
ALREADY WRITING CHECKS. THE
ECONOMICS WORK TODAY, NOT
IN 2036. THE ENVIRONMENTAL
MATH IS NOT JUST
NEUTRAL. IT IS REGENERATIVE.
EVERY ARGUMENT FOR PUTTING
DATA CENTERS IN OUTER
SPACE IS AN ARGUMENT
THAT WORKS BETTER IN
INNER SPACE. AND THERE
IS ONE ARGUMENT THAT
OUTER SPACE CANNOT MAKE
IT ALL. THAT IT
TAKES CARE OF THE
PEOPLE AND THE INDUSTRIES
THAT SPENT THEIR LIVES
BUILDING THE OFFSHORE WORLD
WE ALREADY HAVE. WE
DO NOT NEED TO
SOLVE THE HARDEST PROBLEM
IN ENGINEERING TO BUILD
THE NEXT GENERATION OF
DATA CENTERS. WE NEED
TO SOLVE THE OBVIOUS
ONE. AND THE COMPANIES
THAT BUILT THE OFFSHORE
WORLD, THEY ALREADY KNOW
INNER SPACE IS NOT
WAITING ANYMORE. IT IS
MOVING.