IN DECEMBER 2025, A
STARTUP CALLED STARCLOUD PUT
A SINGLE NVIDIA H100
GPU INTO ORBIT, 60
KILOGRAMS, ONE CHIP. THEY
TRAINED A SMALL LANGUAGE
MODEL ON IT, AND
INVESTORS RESPONDED WITH $170
MILLION AND A BILLION
VALUATION.
TWO MONTHS LATER, THEY
FILED WITH THE FCC
TO BUILD A CONSTELLATION
OF 88 ,000 SATELLITES.
THAT WOULD BE NEARLY
NINE TIMES THE SIZE
OF STARLINK, NOT FOR
INTERNET, FOR COMPUTING.
MEANWHILE, ON THE OTHER
SIDE OF THIS STORY,
70 ,000 OFFSHORE OIL
WORKERS IN THE UK
HAVE LOST THEIR JOBS
IN THE LAST DECADE,
IN THE GULF OF
MEXICO, NEARLY 100 ,000
MORE. ENTIRE COMMUNITIES BUILT
AROUND THE OCEAN, THE
RIGS, THE SUPPLY BOATS,
THE WELDING SHOPS ARE
WATCHING THEIR INDUSTRY DIE.
AND ALMOST NOBODY IS
CONNECTING THESE TWO FACTS.
TO BE FAIR, THE
OUTER SPACE PITCH IS
COMPELLING. IN ORBIT, SOLAR
PANELS GENERATE ROUGHLY FIVE
TIMES MORE ENERGY THAN
ON THE GROUND. NO
CLOUDS, NO NIGHT CYCLE
IN A SUN'S SYNCHRONOUS
ORBIT, NO ATMOSPHERE TO
FILTER THE LIGHT. RADIATIVE
COOLING TO THE VACUUM
OF SPACE MEANS YOU
NEVER NEED WATER FOR
COOLING, AND YOU NEVER
HAVE TO NEGOTIATE WITH
A COUNTY PLANNING BOARD
FOR A BUILDING PERMIT.
THE MONEY IS REAL.
STAR CLOUD, BACKED BY
BENCHMARK AND EQT, HAS
RAISED $200 MILLION AND
IS BUILDING ITS SECOND
SATELLITE FOR OCTOBER LAUNCH.
ORBITAL, FUNDED BY ANDRESEN
HOROWITZ JUST THIS MONTH,
IS TARGETING AN APRIL
2027 TEST FLIGHT WITH
NVIDIA GPUS. THALES, THE
EUROPEAN DEFENSE GIANT, HAS
A CONCEPT DESIGN FOR
A 10 MEGAWATT ORBITAL
DATA CENTER, BUT THEIR
TARGET DATE IS 2036,
AND GOOGLE AND NVIDIA
HAVE RUN EXPLORATORY JOINT
TESTS.
THE LONG -TERM VISION
GOES EVEN FURTHER. SOME
PROPONENTS INVOKE THE DYSON
SPHERE, THE THEORETICAL STRUCTURE
THAT CAPTURES ALL ENERGY
FROM A STAR. SPACE
DATA CENTERS, THEY ARGUE,
ARE THE FIRST STEP
TOWARD THAT FUTURE. IT
IS A BEAUTIFUL IDEA.
BUT THERE IS A
PROBLEM.
A 10 -MEGAWATT DATA
CENTER IN OUTER SPACE,
ROUGHLY ENOUGH TO RUN
A MID -SIZE AI
TRAINING CLUSTER, WOULD COST
BETWEEN $1 .6 AND
$11 BILLION IN CAPITAL
ALONE. ITS OPERATIONAL LIFESPAN?
TWO TO FIVE YEARS.
THERE IS NO MAINTENANCE.
WHEN A COMPONENT FAILS,
THE ENTIRE SATELLITE IS
A WRITE -OFF. YOU
CANNOT SEND A TECHNICIAN
TO LOW -EARTH ORBIT.
A 10 -MEGAWATT DATA
CENTER IN INNER SPACE,
FLOATING ON AN OFFSHORE
WIND PLATFORM OR HOUSED
INSIDE A REPURPOSED OIL
RIG, COSTS BETWEEN $160
AND $530 MILLION. IT
LASTS 25 TO 30
YEARS. AND WHEN SOMETHING
BREAKS, YOU DISPATCH A
REMOTELY OPERATED VEHICLE, AN
ROV, $30 ,000 A
DAY TO RENT. THEY
ALREADY EXIST BY THE
THOUSANDS.
OVER 25 YEARS, THE
TOTAL COST OF OWNERSHIP
FOR A 10 -MEGAWATT
OUTER SPACE DATA CENTER
EXCEEDS $25 BILLION. REPLACEMENTS,
LAUNCHES, ORBITAL DECAY, INSURANCE,
IF YOU CAN EVEN
GET IT. THE SAME
CAPACITY IN THE OCEAN?
3 TO 4 BILLION
TOTAL. PLATFORM, POWER, COOLING,
MAINTENANCE, EVERYTHING.
AND THEN, THERE IS
LATENCY. A DATA CENTER
IN LOW -EARTH ORBIT
ADDS 20 TO 50
MILLISECONDS OF ROUND -TRIP
DELAY. FOR AI INFERENCE,
THE WORKLOAD THAT ACTUALLY
MAKES MONEY, THE ONE
THAT ANSWERS YOUR QUESTIONS
AND GENERATES YOUR IMAGES
IN REAL TIME, THAT
DELAY IS A DEAL
-BREAKER. AN OCEAN DATA
CENTER 130 KILOMETERS OFFSHORE,
0 .65 MILLISECONDS, EFFECTIVELY
INVISIBLE.
IN 2018, MICROSOFT SANK
864 SERVERS TO THE
BOTTOM OF THE OCEAN
OFF SCOTLAND, PROJECT NADEK.
THEY SEALED THEM IN
A NITROGEN -FILLED CAPSULE,
DROPPED IT 35 METERS
DOWN, AND LEFT IT
THERE FOR TWO YEARS.
THE RESULTS WERE REMARKABLE.
THE FAILURE RATE WAS
EIGHT TIMES LOWER THAN
AN EQUIVALENT LAND -BASED
DATA CENTER. EIGHT TIMES.
THE COLD, STABLE TEMPERATURE
OF THE DEEP OCEAN
AND THE ABSENCE OF
HUMAN INTERVENTION. NO ONE
OPENING DOORS, NO DUST,
NO HUMIDITY FLUCTUATIONS. MADE
THE SERVERS DRAMATICALLY MORE
RELIABLE.
MICROSOFT CANCELED NAIDIC IN
2024, NOT BECAUSE IT
FAILED. IT WAS ONE
OF THE MOST SUCCESSFUL
INFRASTRUCTURE EXPERIMENTS OF THE
DECADE. THEY CANCELED IT
BECAUSE THEY NEEDED HYPERSCALE
CAMPUS CAPACITY FOR AI,
AND THE POD MODEL
DID NOT FIT THAT
STRATEGY. THE TECHNOLOGY WAS
PROVEN. THE BUSINESS CASE
JUST POINTED SOMEWHERE ELSE,
BUT OTHER COMPANIES WERE
PAYING ATTENTION.
IN HAINAN, CHINA, HIGHLANDER
HAS DEPLOYED THE WORLD'S
FIRST COMMERCIAL UNDERWATER DATA
CENTER. OPERATIONAL RIGHT NOW,
1200 SERVERS IN SEALED
CAPSULES ON THE SEAFLOOR
WITH PLANS FOR 100
CAPSULES. THEY HAVE CONNECTED
A SEPARATE FACILITY NEAR
SHANGHAI DIRECTLY TO AN
OFFSHORE WIND FARM, THE
FIRST WIND -POWERED UNDERWATER
DATA CENTER ON EARTH.
IN THE NORTH SEA,
IKEDO TECHNOLOGIES IS DEPLOYING
A PROTOTYPE THIS YEAR,
A FLOATING WIND PLATFORM
WITH A DATA CENTER
BUILT INTO THE BALLAST
TANKS UNDERNEATH. NVIDIA IS
A PARTNER. THEIR COMMERCIAL
LAUNCH TARGETS THE UK
IN 2028, PROJECTED PUE
1 .08. IN CALIFORNIA,
NAUTILUS DATA TECHNOLOGIES BUILT
A 7 -MEGAWATT FLOATING
DATA CENTER IN STOCKTON,
A BARGE THAT USES
RIVER WATER FOR COOLING,
86 % OCCUPIED. IN
THE GULF OF MEXICO,
HYPERSCALE DATA RAN A
DATA CENTER ON A
REPURPOSED OIL PLATFORM FROM
NOVEMBER 2024 THROUGH FEBRUARY
2025, PROVING THE CONCEPT
WITH EXISTING INFRASTRUCTURE.
BELOW THE SURFACE, NETWORK
OCEAN, A Y -COMBINATOR
STARTUP, IS TESTING A
1 -MEGAWATT UNDERWATER CAPSULE
IN SAN FRANCISCO BAY.
SUBSEA CLOUD HAS PROJECTS
IN WASHINGTON STATE, THE
GULF OF MEXICO, AND
THE NORTH SEA. THESE
ARE NOT CONCEPTS, THEY
ARE IN THE WATER.
HERE IS SOMETHING MOST
PEOPLE DO NOT REALIZE.
99 % OF ALL
INTERNATIONAL INTERNET TRAFFIC ALREADY
TRAVELS THROUGH THE OCEAN.
1 .5 MILLION KILOMETERS
OF SUBMARINE FIBER OPTIC
CABLE SIT ON THE
SEA FLOOR RIGHT NOW.
THE BACKBONE OF THE
INTERNET IS NOT IN
THE CLOUD. IT IS
IN INNER SPACE. AN
OCEAN DATA CENTER DOES
NOT NEED A NEW
NETWORK. IT PLUGS INTO
THE ONE THAT ALREADY
EXISTS.
THERE ARE 12 ,000
OFFSHORE OIL AND GAS
PLATFORMS IN THE WORLD.
MANY ARE APPROACHING END
OF LIFE, AND HERE
IS THE ABSURDITY. GOVERNMENTS
ARE ABOUT TO SPEND
STAGGERING AMOUNTS OF MONEY
TO DESTROY THEM. THE
UK ALONE HAS BUDGETED
44 BILLION POUNDS, 56
BILLION DOLLARS, TO DECOMMISSION
ITS NORTH SEA PLATFORMS.
THE GULF OF MEXICO
FACES 40 TO 70
BILLION IN DEMOLITION COSTS.
EVERY ONE OF THOSE
PLATFORMS ALREADY HAS GAS
TURBINES FOR POWER, CRANES
FOR LIFTING EQUIPMENT, HELIPADS
FOR ACCESS, AND SEAWATER
INTAKES FOR COOLING. EVERYTHING
A DATA CENTER NEEDS.
WE ARE PAYING TO
DEMOLISH READY -MADE INTER
-SPACE DATA CENTER SITES
WHILE POURING VENTURE CAPITAL
INTO OUTER SPACE ONES.
AND THOSE PLATFORMS WERE
NOT BUILT BY SOFTWARE
ENGINEERS. THEY WERE BUILT
BY MARINE ELECTRICIANS, ROV
OPERATORS, SUBSEA CABLE CREWS,
CRANE OPERATORS, AND PLATFORM
MANAGERS. THE SAME PEOPLE
WHO ARE NOW BEING
LAID OFF AT A
RATE OF 400 EVERY
TWO WEEKS IN THE
UK ALONE. ABERDEEN, THE
OIL CAPITAL OF EUROPE,
HAS LOST 18 ,000
JOBS SINCE 2014. IT
IS ONE OF ONLY
TWO CITIES IN THE
ENTIRE UK WITH FEWER
JOBS THAN IT HAD
IN 2010. IN LOUISIANA,
25 ,000 OFFSHORE WORKERS
HAVE LOST THEIR JOBS
SINCE 2014. OIL WENT
FROM A THIRD OF
THE STATE ECONOMY TO
14%. IN NORWAY, EQUINOR
EXPECTS 10 ,000 EMPLOYEES
TO RETIRE BY 2030,
THE LARGEST RESTRUCTURING IN
THE COMPANY'S 20 -YEAR
HISTORY. 48 % OF
US ENERGY WORKERS ARE
45 OR OLDER, AGING
OUT OF AN INDUSTRY
WITH NO REPLACEMENT PIPELINE.
BUT HERE IS WHAT
MAKES THIS STORY SO
FRUSTRATING. THESE WORKERS ALREADY
HAVE THE SKILLS. AN
ROV OPERATOR WHO INSPECTED
SUBSEA PIPELINES FOR 30
YEARS CAN INSPECT SUBSEA
DATA CENTER PODS WITH
THE EXACT SAME EQUIPMENT.
A SUBSEA ENGINEER WHO
DESIGNED PRESSURE VESSELS FOR
OIL, THE SAME PRESSURE
VESSEL'S HOUSE UNDERWATER SERVERS,
MARINE ELECTRICIANS, SUBSEA CABLE
CREWS, CRANE OPERATORS. THESE
ARE NOT ADJACENT SKILLS.
THEY ARE IDENTICAL JOBS
WITH A DIFFERENT MISSION.
OEUK, THE UK'S OFFSHORE
ENERGY TRADE BODY, FOUND
THAT 90 % OF
OIL AND GAS SKILLS
ARE DIRECTLY TRANSFERABLE, NOT
50, NOT 70, 90.
ONE OFFSHORE WORKER PUT
IT SIMPLY. AS LONG
AS IT PAID THE
BILLS, IT WOULDN'T MATTER
TO ME. IF I
CAN COME HOME TO
MY FAMILY, THAT'S WHAT
MATTERS. A UNION ENGINEER
SAID, RIGGING IS RIGGING.
IT DOESN'T MATTER IF
YOU'RE ON AN OIL
RIG IN A FABRICATION
YARD OR ON A
ONE TURBINE.
RIGHT NOW, THE GLOBAL
OIL INDUSTRY FLARES 151
BILLION CUBIC METERS OF
NATURAL GAS EVERY YEAR.
JUST BURNS IT. WASTED.
THAT IS ENOUGH ENERGY
TO POWER EVERY DATA
CENTER IN THE UNITED
STATES. CRUSOE ENERGY PROVED
THE MODEL ON LAND.
DATA CENTERS NEXT TO
WELLHEADS. CAPTURING FLARED GAS
FOR ELECTRICITY. 63 %
CO2 REDUCTION VERSUS JUST
LETTING IT BURN. 250
MEGAWATTS DEPLOYED. NOW WORTH
BILLIONS.
AND OFFSHORE WIND IS
NO LONGER EXPERIMENTAL. 84
.5 GIGAWATTS OF CAPACITY
IS INSTALLED WORLDWIDE TODAY.
THAT IS NEARLY ENOUGH
TO POWER EVERY DATA
CENTER ON EARTH. THE
ENERGY IS ALREADY BEING
GENERATED. IT JUST NEEDS
SOMEWHERE TO GO.
LAND -BASED DATA CENTERS
HAVE A WATER PROBLEM
THAT IS GETTING WORSE
EVERY YEAR. IN 2023,
US DATA CENTERS CONSUMED
AN ESTIMATED 66 BILLION
LITERS OF WATER DIRECTLY
AND 800 BILLION LITERS
INDIRECTLY THROUGH ELECTRICITY GENERATION.
GOOGLE ALONE USED 8
.1 BILLION GALLONS. TWO
-THIRDS OF NEW DATA
CENTER CONSTRUCTION IS HAPPENING
IN WATER -STRESSED REGIONS.
AN OCEAN DATA CENTER
USES ZERO FRESH WATER.
THE OCEAN IS THE
HEAT SINK. COLD SEA
WATER FLOWS THROUGH HEAT
EXCHANGERS AND RETURNS A
FEW DEGREES WARMER. NO
EVAPORATIVE COOLING TOWERS. NO
MUNICIPAL WATER DRAW. NO
COMPETING WITH FARMS AND
FAMILIES FOR A RESOURCE
THAT IS RUNNING OUT.
NOW CONSIDER WHAT 88
,000 SATELLITES WOULD DO
TO THE SKY. EACH
FALCON 9 LAUNCH DEPOSITS
ROUGHLY 425 TONS OF
CO2 INTO THE ATMOSPHERE,
BUT THE REAL DAMAGE
IS THE BLACK CARBON.
SOOT PARTICLES INJECTED DIRECTLY
INTO THE STRATOSPHERE, WHERE
THEY ARE 500 TIMES
MORE EFFECTIVE AT TRAPPING
HEAT THAN THE SAME
PARTICLES AT GROUND LEVEL.
A 20 -25 STUDY
FROM ETH ZURICH FOUND
THAT PROJECTED LAUNCH RATES
WILL MEASURABLY SLOW THE
RECOVERY OF THE OZONE
LAYER. EVERY SATELLITE THAT
REACHES END OF LIFE
BURNS UP ON RE
-ENTRY, SCATTERING RARE EARTH
METALS AND ALUMINUM OXIDE
AS AEROSOLS INTO THE
UPPER ATMOSPHERE. NO RECYCLING,
NO RECOVERY, 100 %
E -WASTE, VAPORIZED INTO
THE AIR WE BREATHE.
THERE ARE ALREADY 54
,000 TRACKED OBJECTS IN
ORBIT. THE PREDICTED INTERVAL
BETWEEN SIGNIFICANT COLLISION EVENTS,
THE CRASH CLOCK, SITS
AT 2 .8 DAYS.
ADDING 88 ,000 MORE
OBJECTS TO THAT ENVIRONMENT
IS NOT A CALCULATED
RISK. IT IS A
BET AGAINST PHYSICS.
MEANWHILE, IN INNER SPACE,
SOMETHING UNEXPECTED HAPPENS WHEN
YOU PUT STRUCTURES IN
THE WATER. OIL PLATFORM
BASES IN THE GULF
OF MEXICO HAVE BECOME
SOME OF THE MOST
PRODUCTIVE ARTIFICIAL REEFS ON
THE PLANET, 12 TO
14 ,000 FISH PER
STRUCTURE. THE RIGGS -TO
-RIEFS PROGRAM HAS BEEN
CONVERTING DECOMMISSIONED PLATFORMS INTO
PERMANENT MARINE HABITATS FOR
DECADES. A DATA CENTER
ON A PLATFORM DOES
NOT JUST PRESERVE THE
REEF, IT FUNDS ITS
PROTECTION.
LOOK, I RESPECT THE
AMBITION. THE DREAM OF
COMPUTING AN OUTER SPACE
IS GENUINELY INSPIRING. SOME
DAY MAYBE. BUT A
DYSON SPHERE IS NOT
A ROAD MAP. IT
IS A THOUGHT EXPERIMENT.
MEANWHILE, OFFSHORE WIND IS
ALREADY SPINNING. SUBMARINE CABLES
ARE ALREADY CARRYING YOUR
DATA. OIL PLATFORMS ARE
ALREADY STANDING IN THE
WATER, WAITING FOR THEIR
NEXT JOB.
$200 MILLION BOUGHT ONE
GPU IN ORBIT. THAT
SAME CAPITAL COULD FUND
MULTIPLE MEGAWATT -SCALE OCEAN
DATA CENTERS THAT ARE
OPERATIONAL TODAY. STARCLOUD HAS
RAISED MONEY TO BUILD
A SECOND SATELLITE. IKETO
HAS AN NVIDIA PARTNERSHIP
AND A PROTOTYPE GOING
INTO THE WATER THIS
YEAR. HIGHLANDER IS ALREADY
RUNNING COMMERCIAL OPERATIONS. INNER
SPACE IS NOT A
CONCEPT. IT IS A
BUSINESS.
OUTER SPACE DATA CENTERS
ARE BUILT IN LOS
ANGELES, REDMOND, CAPE CANAVERAL,
SILICON VALLEY. THEY NEED
AEROSPACE ENGINEERS, ORBITAL MECHANIC
SPECIALISTS, SATELLITE SYSTEMS DESIGNERS,
SKILLS THAT DO NOT
EXIST IN OIL COMMUNITIES.
THEY EMPLOY HUNDREDS OF
HIGHLY SPECIALIZED ENGINEERS IN
CITIES THAT ALREADY HAVE
PLENTY OF JOBS. INNER
SPACE DATA CENTERS ARE
BUILT BY MARINE TECHNICIANS,
ROV OPERATORS, SUB -SEA
ENGINEERS, PEOPLE WHO ALREADY
LIVE IN ABERDEEN, HUMA,
STAVANGER, AND A HUNDRED
OTHER COASTAL TOWNS. THEY
DO NOT NEED TO
MOVE TO CALIFORNIA. THEY
RETRAIN FOR A CAREER
THEY HAVE NEVER HEARD
OF. THEY STAY WHERE
THEY ARE AND KEEP
DOING WHAT THEY KNOW
WITH A NEW MISSION.
AND THIS IS NOT
JUST ABOUT THE WORKERS
ON THE PLATFORM. EACH
OFFSHORE ENERGY JOB SUPPORTS
ROUGHLY 1 .8 ADDITIONAL
ONSHORE JOBS. THE SUPPLY
BOAT CREWS, THE PORT
WORKERS, THE WELDING SHOPS,
THE DINERS. IN DEEP
WATER, THAT MULTIPLIER RISES
TO FOUR. ABERDEEN, THE
OIL CAPITAL OF EUROPE,
IS SEARCHING FOR A
NEW IDENTITY. HUMA, LOUISIANA,
THE OFFSHORE CAPITAL OF
THE U .S. GULF,
HAS THE SAME SUPPLY
BOATS THAT COULD SERVICE
DATA CENTER PODS TOMORROW.
THERE IS A PAY
GAP. EXPERIENCED OIL WORKERS
EARN 100 TO 200
THOUSAND DOLLARS. OFFSHORE WIND
PAYS AROUND 72 THOUSAND
AT THE 90TH PERCENTILE.
BUT OCEAN DATA CENTERS
ARE HIGHER MARGIN OPERATIONS
THAN WIND FARMS. THEY
COULD PLAUSIBLY CLOSE THAT
GAP. AND A JOB
THAT EXISTS BEATS A
PERFECT JOB THAT DOES
NOT.
BUT HERE IS THE
PART OF THE STORY
NOBODY SAW COMING. IN
2015, ACCORDING TO RICEAD
ENERGY, GLOBAL CAPITAL EXPENDITURE
ON DATA CENTERS REACHED
$770 BILLION. THAT SURPASSED
UPSTREAM OIL AND GAS
INVESTMENT FOR THE FIRST
TIME IN HISTORY. GOLDMAN
SACHS PROJECTS. DATA CENTER
POWER DEMAND WILL GROW
165 % BY 2030.
THE IEA FORECASTS 945
TERAWATT HOURS. GROWING FOUR
TIMES FASTER THAN EVERY
OTHER SECTOR COMBINED, THE
OIL COMPANIES READ THESE
NUMBERS TOO, AND THEY
ARE NOT SITTING STILL.
CHEVRON IS BUILDING FOUR
GIGAWATTS OF GAS -FIRED
POWER FOUNDRIES, THEIR WORD,
CO -LOCATED DIRECTLY WITH
DATA CENTERS. BEHIND THE
METER, NO GRID REQUIRED.
THEIR CEO CALLED IT
A CORRAL THAT IT
REALLY DOES MAKE GOOD
SENSE. EXXONMOBIL IS CONSTRUCTING
A 1 .2 GIGAWATT
GAS PLANT WITH 90
% CARBON CAPTURE, PURPOSE
-BUILT FOR A HYPERSCALER
DATA CENTER. THEIR CEO'S
PITCH TO INVESTORS, WE
WILL BRING THIS ON
FASTER THAN ANYBODY ELSE.
TOTAL ENERGIES HAS SIGNED
CONTRACTS WITH GOOGLE TO
POWER DUTCH DATA CENTERS
AND A 610 GIGAWATT
HOUR DEAL WITH DATA
FOR IN SPAIN. EQUINOR
CREATED AN ENTIRELY NEW
BUSINESS UNIT IN APRIL
2025, JUST CALLED IT
POWER, CITING GROWING DEMAND
FROM AI AND DATA
CENTERS. AND IN MARCH
OF THIS YEAR, ACREBP
AND ARMADA PUT THE
FIRST AI DATA CENTER
ON A LIVE OFFSHORE
OIL PLATFORM ON THE
NORWEGIAN CONTINENTAL SHELF. THEY
CALLED IT A REFERENCE
SYSTEM. THAT IS AN
OIL INDUSTRY TERM. IT
MEANS A TEMPLATE TO
COPY EVERYWHERE.
THE INFRASTRUCTURE IS THERE,
THE POWER IS THERE,
THE COOLING IS LITERALLY
INFINITE, THE WORKFORCE ALREADY
ARE ALREADY WRITING CHECKS,
THE ECONOMICS WORK TODAY,
NOT IN 2036. THE
ENVIRONMENTAL MATH IS NOT
JUST NEUTRAL, IT IS
REGENERATIVE. EVERY ARGUMENT FOR
PUTTING DATA CENTERS IN
OUTER SPACE IS AN
ARGUMENT THAT WORKS BETTER
IN INNER SPACE AND
THERE IS ONE ARGUMENT
THAT OUTER SPACE CANNOT
MAKE IT ALL, THAT
THE PEOPLE AND THE
INDUSTRIES THAT SPENT THEIR
LIVES BUILDING THE OFFSHORE
WE DO NOT NEED
TO SOLVE THE HARDEST
PROBLEM IN ENGINEERING TO
BUILD THE NEXT GENERATION
OF DATA CENTERS. WE
NEED TO SOLVE THE
OBVIOUS ONE. AND THE
COMPANIES THAT BUILT THE
OFFSHORE WORLD? THEY ALREADY
KNOW. INNER SPACE IS
NOT WAITING ANYMORE. IT
IS MOVING.