IN DECEMBER 2025, A
STARTUP CALLED STARCLOUD PUT
A SINGLE NVIDIA H100
GPU INTO ORBIT. 60
KILOGRAMS, ONE CHIP. THEY
TRAINED A SMALL LANGUAGE
MODEL ON IT, AND
INVESTORS RESPONDED WITH $170
MILLION AND A BILLION
-DOLLAR VALUATION. TWO MONTHS
LATER, THEY FILED WITH
THE FCC TO BUILD
A CONSTELLATION OF 88
,000 SATELLITES. THAT WOULD
BE NEARLY NINE TIMES
THE SIZE OF STARLINK.
NOT FOR INTERNET. FOR
COMPUTING. MEANWHILE, ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF THIS
STORY, 70 ,000 OFFSHORE
OIL WORKERS IN THE
UK HAVE LOST THEIR
JOBS IN THE LAST
DECADE. IN THE GULF
OF MEXICO, NEARLY 100
,000 MORE. ENTIRE COMMUNITIES
BUILT AROUND THE OCEAN,
THE RIGS, THE SUPPLY
BOATS, THE WELDING SHOPS,
ARE WATCHING THEIR INDUSTRY
DIE. AND ALMOST NOBODY
IS CONNECTING THESE TWO
FACTS. THIS IS THAT
STORY. TO BE FAIR,
THE OUTER SPACE PITCH
IS COMPELLING. IN ORBIT,
SOLAR PANELS GENERATE ROUGHLY
FIVE TIMES MORE ENERGY
THAN ON THE GROUND.
NO CLOUDS, NO NIGHT
CYCLE IN A SUN'S
SYNCHRONOUS ORBIT, NO ATMOSPHERE
TO FILTER THE LIGHT.
RADIATIVE COOLING TO THE
VACUUM OF SPACE MEANS
YOU NEVER NEED WATER
FOR COOLING, AND YOU
NEVER HAVE TO NEGOTIATE
WITH A COUNTY PLANNING
BOARD FOR A BUILDING
PERMIT. THE MONEY IS
REAL. STARCLOUD, BACKED BY
BENCHMARK AND EQT, HAS
RAISED $200 MILLION AND
IS BUILDING ITS SECOND
SATELLITE FOR OCTOBER LAUNCH.
ORBITAL, FUNDED BY ANDREESSEN
HOROWITZ JUST THIS MONTH,
IS TARGETING AN APRIL
2027 TEST FLIGHT WITH
NVIDIA GPUS. THALES, THE
EUROPEAN DEFENSE GIANT, HAS
A CONCEPT DESIGNED FOR
A 10 -MEGAWATT ORBITAL
DATA CENTER, BUT THEIR
TARGET DATE IS 2036,
AND GOOGLE AND NVIDIA
HAVE RUN EXPLORATORY JOINT
TESTS. THE LONG -TERM
VISION GOES EVEN FURTHER.
SOME PROPONENTS INVOKE THE
DYSON SPHERE, THE THEORETICAL
STRUCTURE THAT CAPTURES ALL
ENERGY FROM A STAR.
SPACE DATA CENTERS, THEY
ARGUE, ARE THE FIRST
STEP TOWARD THAT FUTURE.
IT IS A BEAUTIFUL
IDEA, BUT THERE IS
A PROBLEM. A 10
-MEGAWATT DATA CENTER IN
OUTER SPACE, ROUGHLY ENOUGH
TO RUN A MID
-SIZE AI TRAINING CLUSTER,
WOULD COST BETWEEN $1
.6 AND $11 BILLION
IN CAPITAL ALONE. ITS
OPERATIONAL LIFESPAN? TWO TO
FIVE YEARS. THERE IS
NO MAINTENANCE. WHEN A
COMPONENT FAILS, THE ENTIRE
SATELLITE IS A WRITE
-OFF. YOU CANNOT SEND
A TECHNICIAN TO LOW
-EARTH ORBIT. A 10
-MEGAWATT DATA CENTER IN
INNER SPACE, FLOATING ON
AN OFFSHORE WIND PLATFORM
OR HOUSED INSIDE A
REPURPOSED OIL RIG, COSTS
BETWEEN $160 AND $530
MILLION. IT LASTS 25
TO 30 YEARS. AND
WHEN SOMETHING BREAKS, YOU
DISPATCH A REMOTELY OPERATED
VEHICLE, AN ROV, $30
,000 A DAY TO
RENT. THEY ALREADY EXIST
BY THE THOUSANDS. OVER
25 YEARS, THE TOTAL
COST OF OWNERSHIP FOR
A 10 -MEGAWATT OUTER
SPACE DATA CENTER EXCEEDS
$25 BILLION. REPLACEMENTS, LAUNCHES,
ORBITAL DECAY, INSURANCE, IF
YOU CAN EVEN GET
IT. THE SAME CAPACITY
IN THE OCEAN? THREE
TO FOUR BILLION TOTAL.
PLATFORM, POWER, COOLING, MAINTENANCE,
EVERYTHING. AND THEN THERE
IS LATENCY. A DATA
CENTER IN LOW -EARTH
ORBIT ADDS 20 TO
50 MILLISECONDS OF ROUND
-TRIP DELAY. FOR AI
INFERENCE, THE WORKLOAD THAT
ACTUALLY MAKES MONEY, THE
ONE THAT ANSWERS YOUR
QUESTIONS AND GENERATES YOUR
IMAGES IN REAL TIME,
THAT DELAY IS A
DEAL BREAKER. AN OCEAN
DATA CENTER 130 KILOMETERS
OFFSHORE, 0 .65 MILLISECONDS,
EFFECTIVELY INVISIBLE. IN 2018,
MICROSOFT SANK 864 SERVERS
TO THE BOTTOM OF
THE OCEAN OFF SCOTLAND,
PROJECT NATICK. THEY SEALED
THEM IN A NITROGEN
-FILLED CAPSULE, DROPPED IT
35 METERS DOWN, AND
LEFT IT THERE FOR
TWO YEARS. THE RESULTS
WERE REMARKABLE. THE FAILURE
RATE WAS EIGHT TIMES
LOWER THAN AN EQUIVALENT
LAND -BASED DATA CENTER.
EIGHT TIMES. THE COLD,
STABLE TEMPERATURE OF THE
DEEP OCEAN AND THE
ABSENCE OF HUMAN INTERVENTION.
NO ONE OPENING DOORS,
NO DUST, NO HUMIDITY
FLUCTUATIONS MADE THE SERVERS
DRAMATICALLY MORE RELIABLE. MICROSOFT
CANCELED NATICK IN 2024,
NOT BECAUSE IT FAILED.
IT WAS ONE OF
THE MOST SUCCESSFUL INFRASTRUCTURE
EXPERIMENTS OF THE DECADE.
THEY CANCELED IT BECAUSE
THEY NEEDED HYPERSCALE CAMPUS
CAPACITY FOR AI AND
THE POD MODEL DID
NOT FIT THAT STRATEGY.
THE TECHNOLOGY WAS PROVEN.
THE BUSINESS CASE JUST
POINTED SOMEWHERE ELSE, BUT
OTHER COMPANIES WERE PAYING
ATTENTION. IN HAINAN, CHINA,
HIGHLANDER HAS DEPLOYED THE
WORLD'S FIRST COMMERCIAL UNDERWATER
DATA CENTER. OPERATIONAL RIGHT
NOW, 1 ,200 SERVERS
IN SEALED CAPSULES ON
THE SEAFLOOR WITH PLANS
FOR 100 CAPSULES. THEY
HAVE CONNECTED A SEPARATE
FACILITY NEAR SHANGHAI DIRECTLY
TO AN OFFSHORE WIND
FARM, THE FIRST WIND
-POWERED UNDERWATER DATA CENTER
ON EARTH. IN THE
NORTH SEA, AIKIDO TECHNOLOGIES
IS DEPLOYING A PROTOTYPE
THIS YEAR, A FLOATING
WIND PLATFORM WITH A
DATA CENTER BUILT INTO
THE BALLAST TANKS UNDERNEATH.
NVIDIA IS A PARTNER.
THEIR COMMERCIAL LAUNCH TARGETS
THE UK IN 2028.
PROJECTED PUE? 1 .08.
IN CALIFORNIA, NAUTILUS DATA
TECHNOLOGIES BUILT A 7
-MEGAWATT FLOATING DATA CENTER
IN STOCKTON, A BARGE
THAT USES RIVER WATER
FOR COOLING. 86 %
OCCUPIED. IN THE GULF
OF MEXICO, HYPERSCALE DATA
RAN A DATA CENTER
ON A REPURPOSED OIL
PLATFORM FROM NOVEMBER 2024
THROUGH FEBRUARY 2025, PROVING
THE CONCEPT WITH EXISTING
INFRASTRUCTURE. BELOW THE SURFACE,
NETWORK OCEAN, A Y
-COMBINATOR STARTUP, IS TESTING
A 1 -MEGAWATT UNDERWATER
CAPSULE IN SAN FRANCISCO
BAY. SUBSEA CLOUD HAS
PROJECTS IN WASHINGTON STATE,
THE GULF OF MEXICO,
AND THE NORTH SEA.
THESE ARE NOT CONCEPTS.
THEY ARE IN THE
WATER. HERE IS SOMETHING
MOST PEOPLE DO NOT
REALIZE. 99 % OF
ALL INTERNATIONAL INTERNET TRAFFIC
ALREADY TRAVELS THROUGH THE
OCEAN. 1 .5 MILLION
KILOMETERS OF SUBMARINE FIBER
-OPTIC CABLE SIT ON
THE SEA FLOOR RIGHT
NOW. THE BACKBONE OF
THE INTERNET IS NOT
IN THE CLOUD. IT
IS IN INNER SPACE.
AN OCEAN DATA CENTER
DOES NOT NEED A
NEW NETWORK. IT PLUGS
INTO THE ONE THAT
ALREADY EXISTS. THERE ARE
12 ,000 OFFSHORE OIL
AND GAS PLATFORMS IN
THE WORLD. MANY ARE
APPROACHING END OF LIFE.
AND HERE IS THE
ABSURDITY. GOVERNMENTS ARE ABOUT
TO SPEND STAGGERING AMOUNTS
OF MONEY TO DESTROY
THEM. THE UK ALONE
HAS BUDGETED £44 BILLION,
£56 BILLION, TO DECOMMISSION
ITS NORTH SEA PLATFORMS.
THE GULF OF MEXICO
FACES 40 TO 70
BILLION IN DEMOLITION COSTS.
EVERY ONE OF THOSE
PLATFORMS ALREADY HAS GAS
TURBINES FOR POWER, CRANES
FOR LIFTING EQUIPMENT, HELIPADS
FOR ACCESS, AND SEAWATER
INTAKES FOR COOLING. EVERYTHING
A DATA CENTER NEEDS,
WE ARE PAYING TO
DEMOLISH READY -MADE INNER
SPACE DATA CENTER SITES
WHILE POURING VENTURE CAPITAL
INTO OUTER SPACE ONES.
AND THOSE PLATFORMS WERE
NOT BUILT BY SOFTWARE
ENGINEERS. THEY WERE BUILT
BY MARINE ELECTRICIANS, ROV
OPERATORS, SUBSEA CABLE CREWS,
CRANE OPERATORS, AND PLATFORM
MANAGERS. THE SAME PEOPLE
WHO ARE NOW BEING
LAID OFF AT A
RATE OF 400 EVERY
TWO WEEKS IN THE
UK ALONE. ABERDEEN, THE
OIL CAPITAL OF EUROPE,
HAS LOST 18 ,000
JOBS SINCE 2014. IT
IS ONE OF ONLY
TWO CITIES IN THE
ENTIRE UK WITH FEWER
JOBS THAN IT HAD
IN 2010. IN LOUISIANA,
25 ,000 OFFSHORE WORKERS
HAVE LOST THEIR JOBS
SINCE 2014. OIL WENT
FROM A THIRD OF
THE STATE ECONOMY TO
14%. IN NORWAY, EQUINOR
EXPECTS 10 ,000 EMPLOYEES
TO RETIRE BY 2030,
THE LARGEST RESTRUCTURING IN
THE COMPANY'S 20 -YEAR
HISTORY. 48 % OF
US ENERGY WORKERS ARE
45 OR OLDER, AGING
OUT OF AN INDUSTRY
WITH NO REPLACEMENT PIPELINE.
BUT HERE IS WHAT
MAKES THIS STORY SO
FRUSTRATING. THESE WORKERS ALREADY
HAVE THE SKILLS. AN
ROV OPERATOR WHO INSPECTED
SUBSEA PIPELINES FOR 30
YEARS CAN INSPECT SUBSEA
DATA CENTER PODS WITH
THE EXACT SAME EQUIPMENT.
A SUBSEA ENGINEER WHO
DESIGNED PRESSURE VESSELS FOR
OIL? THE SAME PRESSURE
VESSELS HOUSE UNDERWATER SERVERS,
MARINE ELECTRICIANS, SUBSEA CABLE
CREWS, CRANE OPERATORS. THESE
ARE NOT ADJACENT SKILLS.
THEY ARE IDENTICAL JOBS
WITH A DIFFERENT MISSION.
OEUK, THE UK'S OFFSHORE
ENERGY TRADE BODY, FOUND
THAT 90 % OF
OIL AND GAS SKILLS
ARE DIRECTLY TRANSFERABLE, NOT
50, NOT 70, 90.
ONE OFFSHORE WORKER PUT
IT SIMPLY, AS LONG
AS IT PAID THE
BILLS, IT WOULDN'T MATTER
TO ME. IF I
CAN COME HOME TO
MY FAMILY, THAT'S WHAT
MATTERS. A UNION ENGINEER
SAID, RIGGING IS RIGGING.
IT DOESN'T MATTER IF
YOU'RE ON AN OIL
RIG IN A FABRICATION
YARD OR ON A
WINE TURBINE. RIGHT NOW,
THE GLOBAL OIL INDUSTRY
FLARES 151 BILLION CUBIC
METERS OF NATURAL GAS
EVERY YEAR. JUST BURNS
IT. WASTED. THAT IS
ENOUGH ENERGY TO POWER
EVERY DATA CENTER IN
THE UNITED STATES. CRUSOE
ENERGY PROVED THE MODEL
ON LAND. DATA CENTERS
NEXT TO WELLHEADS. CAPTURING
FLARED GAS FOR ELECTRICITY.
63 % CO2 REDUCTION
VERSUS JUST LETTING IT
BURN. 250 MEGAWATTS DEPLOYED.
NOW WORTH BILLIONS. AND
OFFSHORE WIND IS NO
LONGER EXPERIMENTAL. 84 .5
GIGAWATTS OF CAPACITY IS
INSTALLED WORLDWIDE TODAY. THAT
IS NEARLY ENOUGH TO
POWER EVERY DATA CENTER
ON EARTH. THE ENERGY
IS ALREADY BEING GENERATED.
IT JUST NEEDS SOMEWHERE
TO GO. LAND -BASED
DATA CENTERS HAVE A
WATER PROBLEM THAT IS
GETTING WORSE EVERY YEAR.
IN 2023, U .S.
DATA CENTERS CONSUMED AN
ESTIMATED 66 BILLION LITERS
OF WATER DIRECTLY AND
800 BILLION LITERS INDIRECTLY
THROUGH ELECTRICITY GENERATION. GOOGLE
ALONE USED 8 .1
BILLION GALLONS. TWO -THIRDS
OF NEW DATA CENTER
CONSTRUCTION IS HAPPENING IN
WATER -STRESSED REGIONS. AN
OCEAN DATA CENTER USES
ZERO FRESH WATER. THE
OCEAN IS THE HEAT
SINK. COLD SEA WATER
FLOWS THROUGH HEAT EXCHANGERS
AND RETURNS A FEW
DEGREES WARMER. NO EVAPORATIVE
COOLING TOWERS. NO MUNICIPAL
WATER DRAW. NO COMPETING
WITH FARMS AND FAMILIES
FOR A RESOURCE THAT
IS RUNNING OUT. NOW
CONSIDER WHAT 88 ,000
SATELLITES WOULD DO TO
THE SKY. EACH FALCON
9 LAUNCH DEPOSITS ROUGHLY
425 TONS OF CO2
INTO THE ATMOSPHERE. BUT
THE REAL DAMAGE IS
THE BLACK CARBON. SOOT
PARTICLES INJECTED DIRECTLY INTO
THE STRATOSPHERE, WHERE THEY
ARE 500 TIMES MORE
EFFECTIVE AT TRAPPING HEAT
THAN THE SAME PARTICLES
AT GROUND LEVEL. A
2025 STUDY FROM ETH
ZURICH FOUND THAT PROJECTED
LAUNCH RATES WILL MEASURABLY
SLOW THE RECOVERY OF
THE OZONE LAYER. EVERY
SATELLITE THAT REACHES END
OF LIFE BURNS UP
ON RE -ENTRY, SCATTERING
RARE EARTH METALS AND
ALUMINUM OXIDE AS AEROSOLS
INTO THE UPPER ATMOSPHERE.
NO RECYCLING. NO RECOVERY.
100 % E -WASTE
VAPORIZED INTO THE AIR
WE BREATHE. THERE ARE
ALREADY 54 ,000 TRACKED
OBJECTS IN ORBIT. THE
PREDICTED INTERVAL BETWEEN SIGNIFICANT
COLLISION EVENTS, THE CRASH
CLOCK, SITS AT 2
.8 DAYS. ADDING 88
,000 MORE OBJECTS TO
THAT ENVIRONMENT IS NOT
A CALCULATED RISK. IT
IS A BET AGAINST
PHYSICS. MEANWHILE, IN INNER
SPACE, SOMETHING UNEXPECTED HAPPENS
WHEN YOU PUT STRUCTURES
IN THE WATER. OIL
PLATFORM BASES IN THE
GULF OF MEXICO HAVE
BECOME SOME OF THE
MOST PRODUCTIVE ARTIFICIAL REEFS
ON THE PLANET. 12
TO 14 ,000 FISH
PER STRUCTURE. THE RIGS
TO REEFS PROGRAM HAS
BEEN CONVERTING DECOMMISSIONED PLATFORMS
INTO PERMANENT MARINE HABITATS
FOR DECADES. A DATA
CENTER ON A PLATFORM
DOES NOT JUST PRESERVE
THE REEF. IT FUNDS
ITS PROTECTION. LOOK, I
RESPECT THE AMBITION. THE
DREAM OF COMPUTING IN
OUTER SPACE IS GENUINELY
INSPIRING. SOMEDAY MAYBE. BUT
A DYSON SPHERE IS
NOT A ROADMAP. IT
IS A THOUGHT EXPERIMENT.
MEANWHILE, OFFSHORE WIND IS
ALREADY SPINNING. SUBMARINE CABLES
ARE ALREADY CARRYING YOUR
DATA. OIL PLATFORMS ARE
ALREADY STANDING IN THE
WATER, WAITING FOR THEIR
NEXT JOB. $200 MILLION
BOUGHT ONE GPU IN
ORBIT. THAT SAME CAPITAL
COULD FUND MULTIPLE MEGAWATT
-SCALE OCEAN DATA CENTERS
THAT ARE OPERATIONAL TODAY.
STARCLOUD HAS RAISED MONEY
TO BUILD A SECOND
SATELLITE. AIKIDO HAS AN
NVIDIA PARTNERSHIP AND A
PROTOTYPE GOING INTO THE
WATER THIS YEAR. HIGHLANDER
IS ALREADY RUNNING COMMERCIAL
OPERATIONS. INNER SPACE IS
NOT A CONCEPT. IT
IS A BUSINESS. OUTER
SPACE DATA CENTERS ARE
BUILT IN LOS ANGELES,
REDMOND, CAPE CANAVERAL, SILICON
VALLEY. THEY NEED AEROSPACE
ENGINEERS, ORBITAL MECHANICS SPECIALISTS,
SATELLITE SYSTEMS DESIGNERS, SKILLS
THAT DO NOT EXIST
IN OIL COMMUNITIES. THEY
EMPLOY HUNDREDS OF HIGHLY
SPECIALIZED ENGINEERS IN CITIES
THAT ALREADY HAVE PLENTY
OF JOBS. INNER SPACE
DATA CENTERS ARE BUILT
BY MARINE TECHNICIANS, ROV
OPERATORS, SUBSEA ENGINEERS, PEOPLE
WHO ALREADY LIVE IN
ABERDEEN, HUMA, STAVANGER, AND
A HUNDRED OTHER COASTAL
TOWNS. THEY DO NOT
NEED TO MOVE TO
CALIFORNIA. THEY DO NOT
NEED TO RETRAIN FOR
A CAREER THEY HAVE
NEVER HEARD OF. THEY
STAY WHERE THEY ARE
AND KEEP DOING WHAT
THEY KNOW WITH A
NEW MISSION. AND THIS
IS NOT JUST ABOUT
THE WORKERS ON THE
PLATFORM. EACH OFFSHORE ENERGY
JOB SUPPORTS ROUGHLY 1
.8 ADDITIONAL ONSHORE JOBS.
THE SUPPLY BOAT CREWS,
THE PORT WORKERS, THE
WELDING SHOPS, THE DINERS.
IN DEEP WATER, THAT
MULTIPLIER RISES TO FOUR.
ABERDEEN, THE OIL CAPITAL
OF EUROPE, IS SEARCHING
FOR A NEW IDENTITY.
HUMA, LOUISIANA, THE OFFSHORE
CAPITAL OF THE U
.S. GULF, HAS THE
SAME SUPPLY BOATS THAT
COULD SERVICE DATA CENTER
PODS TOMORROW. THERE IS
A PAY GAP. EXPERIENCED
OIL WORKERS EARN $100
,000 TO $200 ,000.
OFFSHORE WIND PAYS AROUND
$72 ,000 AT THE
90TH PERCENTILE. BUT OCEAN
DATA CENTERS ARE HIGHER
MARGIN OPERATIONS THAN WIND
FARMS. THEY COULD PLAUSIBLY
CLOSE THAT GAP. AND
A JOB THAT EXISTS
BEATS A PERFECT JOB
THAT DOES NOT. BUT
HERE IS THE PART
OF THE STORY NOBODY
SAW COMING. IN 2005,
ACCORDING TO REISTAD ENERGY,
GLOBAL CAPITAL EXPENDITURE ON
DATA CENTERS REACHED 770
BILLION DOLLARS. THAT SURPASSED
UPSTREAM OIL AND GAS
INVESTMENT FOR THE FIRST
TIME IN HISTORY. GOLDMAN
SACHS PROJECTS. DATA CENTER
POWER DEMAND WILL GROW
165 PERCENT BY 2030.
THE IEA FORECASTS 945
TERAWATT HOURS. GROWING FOUR
TIMES FASTER THAN EVERY
OTHER SECTOR COMBINED, THE
OIL COMPANIES READ THESE
NUMBERS TOO. AND THEY
ARE NOT SITTING STILL.
CHEVRON IS BUILDING FOUR
GIGAWATTS OF GAS FIRED
POWER FOUNDRIES. THEIR WORD.
CO -LOCATED DIRECTLY WITH
DATA CENTERS. BEHIND THE
METER. NO GRID REQUIRED.
THEIR CEO CALLED IT
A CORRAL NET. IT
REALLY DOES MAKE GOOD
SENSE. EXXONMOBIL IS CONSTRUCTING
A 1 .2 GIGAWATT
GAS PLANT WITH 90
PERCENT CARBON CAPTURE PURPOSE
BUILT FOR A HYPERSCALER
DATA CENTER. THEIR CEOS
PITCH TO INVESTORS. WE
WILL BRING THIS ON
FASTER THAN ANYBODY ELSE.
TOTAL ENERGIES HAS SIGNED
CONTRACTS WITH GOOGLE TO
POWER DUTCH DATA CENTERS
AND A 610 GIGAWATT
HOUR DEAL WITH DATA
FOR IN SPAIN. EQUINOR
CREATED AN ENTIRELY NEW
BUSINESS UNIT IN APRIL
2025. JUST CALLED IT
POWER. CITING GROWING DEMAND
FROM A .I. AND
DATA CENTERS. AND IN
MARCH OF THIS YEAR,
ACREBP AND ARMADA PUT
THE FIRST A .I.
DATA CENTER ON A
LIVE OFFSHORE OIL PLATFORM
ON THE NORWEGIAN CONTINENTAL
SHELF. THEY CALLED IT
A REFERENCE SYSTEM. THAT
IS AN OIL INDUSTRY
TERM. IT MEANS A
TEMPLATE TO COPY EVERYWHERE.
THE OIL FIELD SERVICES
COMPANIES ARE MOVING EVEN
FASTER. BAKER HUGHES HAS
BOOKED 1 .2 GIGAWATTS
OF DATA CENTER WORK.
HALLIBURTON'S VOLTAGRID SUBSIDIARY SIGNED
A 2 .3 GIGAWATT
DEAL WITH ORACLE. SLB'S
DIGITAL DIVISION HIT ONE
BILLION DOLLARS IN ANNUAL
RECURRING REVENUE. UP 121
PERCENT YEAR OVER YEAR.
HALLIBURTON'S CEO PUT IT
BLUNTLY. THE DEMAND FOR
POWER AND A .I.
IS LIKE NOTHING I
HAVE EVER SEEN. AND
THE ENERGY IS ALREADY
THERE. ARMADA ESTIMATES SIX
GIGAWATTS OF STRANDED ENERGY
EXISTS IN THE UNITED
STATES ALONE. GAS THAT
IS BEING FLARED OR
SHUT IN. BECAUSE THERE
IS NO PIPELINE TO
TAKE IT ANYWHERE. THAT
IS ENOUGH TO POWER
HUNDREDS OF DATA CENTERS.
SHELL'S LATEST SCENARIOS PREDICT
DATA CENTERS WILL CONSUME
5 ,000 TERAWATT HOURS
BY 2050. ROUGHLY EIGHT
PERCENT OF ALL GLOBAL
ELECTRICITY. THESE COMPANIES BUILT
THE MODERN WORLD. THE
ENERGY THAT POWERED THE
INTERNET. THE CITIES. THE
HOSPITALS. IT CAME FROM
THEM. THEY ARE NOT
THE ENEMY OF WHAT
COMES NEXT. THEY ARE
THE BRIDGE TO IT.
THE PLATFORMS EXIST. THE
WORKFORCE EXISTS. THE LOGISTICS
EXIST. THE ONLY THING
LEFT IS TO POINT
IT ALL IN THE
RIGHT DIRECTION. AND THEY
ALREADY ARE. THE INFRASTRUCTURE
IS THERE. THE POWER
IS THERE. THE COOLING
IS LITERALLY INFINITE. THE
WORKFORCE ALREADY EXISTS. THE
OIL COMPANIES ARE ALREADY
WRITING CHECKS. THE ECONOMICS
WORK TODAY. NOT IN
2036. THE ENVIRONMENTAL MATH
IS NOT JUST NEUTRAL.
IT IS REGENERATIVE. EVERY
ARGUMENT FOR PUTTING DATA
CENTERS IN OUTER SPACE
IS AN ARGUMENT THAT
WORKS BETTER IN INNER
SPACE. AND THERE IS
ONE ARGUMENT THAT OUTER
SPACE CANNOT MAKE IT
ALL. THAT IT TAKES
CARE OF THE PEOPLE
AND THE INDUSTRIES THAT
SPENT THEIR LIVES BUILDING
THE OFFSHORE WORLD WE
ALREADY HAVE. WE DO
NOT NEED TO SOLVE
THE HARDEST PROBLEM IN
ENGINEERING TO BUILD THE
NEXT GENERATION OF DATA
CENTERS. WE NEED TO
SOLVE THE OBVIOUS ONE.
AND THE COMPANIES THAT
BUILT THE OFFSHORE WORLD?
THEY ALREADY KNOW. INNER
SPACE IS NOT WAITING
ANYMORE. IT IS MOVING.